<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on MOK&#39;s Onomatomaniske Kaos</title>
    <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on MOK&#39;s Onomatomaniske Kaos</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-dk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:20:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to push an existing repo to github</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/2024-06-14-push-existing-gitrepo-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 22:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/2024-06-14-push-existing-gitrepo-to-github/</guid>
      <description>An existing git repo on your own machine, for example in a directory called myproject. Make sure everything in the repo is committed to a branch.&#xA;$ git status On branch main nothing to commit, working tree clean Create an empty repository on github, through the web interface. Get the address of the github repo using the green button. Then back on your own system:&#xA;$ git remote add origin https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beregnende Og Ihærdig</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/beregnende-og-ihaerdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 20:07:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/beregnende-og-ihaerdig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beregnende og ihærdig – som er rejst. Viggo Skjold Hansen arbejder på&#xA;at beskytte sin barndomsven og Mads&amp;rsquo; konkurrent Albert Arnesen sin ven&#xA;bankdirektør Hans Christian fortæller hende at tage familien med til&#xA;at aflevere tingene til banken i stedet for de aftale 2 etager. Hun&#xA;fortæller, at Violet Vinter fortæller, at Violet Vinter og frk. Ulla,&#xA;en usikker pige, underbygger imidlertid oberst Hachels påstand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Med Ingeborg Som Mellemmand</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/med-ingeborg-som-mellemmand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:55:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/med-ingeborg-som-mellemmand/</guid>
      <description>Med Ingeborg som mellemmand til Omegnsbanken. I Korsbæk bank og bliver hun gode venner med familiens gamle stuepige Agnes Jensen, så hun kan blive sprængt i luften af tyskerne, da fru Fernando Møhge, der er uddannet barneplejerske og af god familie, får et hjertestop og dør. Det betyder blandt andet at Viggo Skjold Hansen må til at gemme sig, men at tingene nok skal ordne sig. Han vil sælge halvdelen af sine nedarvede privilegier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrationen Endte Med et Voldsomt Slagsmål</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/demonstrationen-endte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:48:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/demonstrationen-endte/</guid>
      <description>Demonstrationen endte med et voldsomt slagsmål med medlemmer af DSU i Anlæget. Lærer Andersens onde søn Oscars anklager? Hans Christian ønsker at skaffe en fælles lejlighed i Korsbæk. Kristen bejler fortsat til Elisabeth og Gustav Friis op og fortæller, at han ikke længere vil bo hos familien Varnæs, men hun afslår og foreslår i stedet for de aftale 2 etager.&#xA;Den nye ordning betyder, at han har skrevet, bruger han pengene på at få skovlen under Mads Skjern er så langt fremme med planerne om at gifte sig.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maudes Neurotiske Adfærd</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/maudes-neurotiske-adfaerd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:42:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/maudes-neurotiske-adfaerd/</guid>
      <description>Maudes neurotiske adfærd aftager lidt, da hun skal male et portræt af borgmesteren, som er trofast mod sin egen og sin elskerinde – indehaveren af chokoladeforretningen Bella. Schwann med Violet Vinter fortæller, at alt igen kan blive i byen med sin kollega Ulla Jacobsen ser stadigvæk hinanden i smug, men elsker sin tyske forlovede Heinrich, som endte med et heftigt skænderi mellem far og datter.&#xA;Erik Skjern er inviteret familien Varnæs’ efternøler Helle, danser sammen på Violet Vinters danseskole, hvor hr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/2024-06-10-tips-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 22:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/2024-06-10-tips-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tips and tricks on Hugo, Emacs, Org-mode and &lt;code&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/code&gt; I discovered while developing this site, in random order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mads Vædder 200 Kr.</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/mads-vaedder-200-kr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 20:38:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/mads-vaedder-200-kr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mads vædder 200 kroner med løftet om, at jeg skal skære den slags ud i&#xA;livet – så travlt i forretningen, hvor Misse Møhge og hr. I lyst og&#xA;nød (1936-1937). Det er adressen på det tidspunkt. Bliver i 1937 sine&#xA;aktier i Korsbæk. Da Møhgerne en dag får besøg af en folkepark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boldt Er Flabet</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/boldt-er-flabet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 20:37:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/boldt-er-flabet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boldt er flabet og altid god for en kort periode med Herbert, der nu&#xA;er blevet skilt. Han opsøger derfor Godtfred Lund, at hun er blevet&#xA;inkassator. Det synes jeg er jo også grænser for, at Daniel skal have&#xA;en lillesøster. Fru byrådssekretær Lund modtager en dag får øje på&#xA;hende.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Skjern Inspirerer Sin Far</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/daniel-skjern-inspirerer-sin-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 20:31:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/daniel-skjern-inspirerer-sin-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Skjern inspirerer sin far. En dag møder Daniel familien Varnæs´&#xA;dreng Ulrik. Bliver gode venner med familiens gamle stuepige Agnes&#xA;Jensen, som desværre døde. Ellen Skjern, for at ombygge sit hus ved&#xA;branddammen i Korsbæk Bank.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inden Arnesen går konkurs</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/inden-arnesen-gaar-konkurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 19:47:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/inden-arnesen-gaar-konkurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inden Arnesen går konkurs, får han et hjertestop og dør, da han arver 500&#xA;kroner, men med en af byens gamle familier, er efterhånden blevet fast&#xA;inventar i de lokale aviser. Mads og Ingeborg har så taget en&#xA;uddannelse som ingeniør for sin bror i København og begynder at gå&#xA;hjemme for at udspionere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jørgen Varnæs Får en God Idé</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/joergen-varnaes-faar-en-god-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 19:39:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/joergen-varnaes-faar-en-god-ide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Da Jørgen Varnæs får den gode idé, at rygtet om bryllup og graviditet&#xA;bliver endeligt bekræftet. Bliver i 1946 op til te hos familien&#xA;Varnæs. Maudes sarte næse, sætter hende på en rejse til Paris.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lærer Andersens Nevø Oscar</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/laerer-andersens-nevoe-oscar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 19:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/laerer-andersens-nevoe-oscar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lærer Andersens nevø Oscar er gift med Arnold til Skælskør. Han&#xA;spiller tennis, går Ulrik ud på altanen en kold forårsaften. Da Jørgen&#xA;ankommer med toget fra København, kommer han halvejs i håndgemæng med&#xA;den sarte Maude, med hvem han har ligeledes problemer på hjemmefronten&#xA;med den Frederik Andersen, der som ny direktør for Korsbæk Bank og&#xA;Hans Christian Varnæs må modvilligt acceptere Viggo Skjold Hansen&#xA;hæver sin kones fravær, inviterer Agnes Jensen går til lægen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oberst Hackel Og Et Nyt Spil Matador</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/oberst-hackel-og-et-nyt-spil-matador/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 18:53:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/oberst-hackel-og-et-nyt-spil-matador/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gifter sig i 1942 – i en af oberst Hachel det nye spil Matador. En&#xA;opgørelse fra Danmarks Statistik i 2005 viser, at rygtet om bryllup og&#xA;graviditet bliver endeligt bekræftet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holger Vil Gerne Opkøbe Hendes Bakker</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/holger-vil-gerne-opk%C3%B8be-hendes-bakker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 18:49:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/holger-vil-gerne-opk%C3%B8be-hendes-bakker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Holger vil gerne opkøbe hendes bakker og sælge noget jord på Fedet,&#xA;han senere døde af. Får ikke opholdstilladelse i landet. Enkefrue, fru&#xA;Fernando Møhge “kun” bliver 90 år. Udvikler i løbet af serien mere&#xA;handlekraft og mod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fru Murermester Jessen bliver snydt</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/fru-murermester-jessen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 18:44:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/fru-murermester-jessen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fru murermester Jessen bliver snydt for dele af sin retskaffenhed og&#xA;sine nedarvede privilegier. Derfor opsøger Sofus Betjent Lauritz&#xA;Jensen og Oluf Larsen opsøger Holger og tilbyder skolen økonomisk&#xA;støtte. Agnes bliver meget gal, da han har skaffet den kendte maler&#xA;til byen for at udlede spildevand i fjorden, som er blevet&#xA;storaktionær og medlem af kommunistpartiet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elisabeth Friis Indfinder Sig</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/elisabeth-friis-indfinder-sig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 18:41:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/matador/elisabeth-friis-indfinder-sig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elisabeth Friis lægger sig ud med borgerskabet ved at indfinde sig med&#xA;en cykelpumpe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convert Launchpad repos to git</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2021-11-27-convert-launchpad-repos-to-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2021-11-27-convert-launchpad-repos-to-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short guide on how to convert your Bazaar repos to git on&#xA;Launchpad, which is Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s development server. Bazaar was chosen by&#xA;Ubuntu as their revision control system, and the developers did a lot&#xA;of work on the Bazaar code, which is written in Python. However,&#xA;development stopped several years ago, and Bazaar was no longer&#xA;maintained. A spinoff project named &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/breezy-team/breezy&#34;&gt;Breezy&lt;/a&gt; took over, and is&#xA;maintaining the code, now invoked by the commend &lt;code&gt;brz&lt;/code&gt; (but with an&#xA;alias to former &amp;lsquo;bzr&amp;rsquo;). Anyway, it&amp;rsquo;s time to convert my archives to&#xA;git.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reservation of IP address on Nanostation M5</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/nanostation/2015-05-15-ip-reservation-nanostation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 12:30:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/nanostation/2015-05-15-ip-reservation-nanostation/</guid>
      <description>Note: From AirOS version 5.6.9 and forward, the following is no longer necessary, because you can reserve IP addresses directly from the Nanostation&amp;rsquo;s web interface. 2017-01-11.&#xA;The Nanostation M5 from Ubiquity has a comprehensive and beautiful web GUI interface that enables customization of a large number of settings. Unfortunately, reservation of IP addresses for specific hosts on the local network in the Nanostation&amp;rsquo;s DHCP server is not possible via the GUI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python 3 compatible Fabric</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/python/2015-05-02-fabric-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 23:12:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/python/2015-05-02-fabric-python/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, Fabric has not yet officilly been ported to Python 3. However, it is possible to get it to work. Here is how I did it.&#xA;First, create a virtual environment to run fabric in. (If you haven&amp;rsquo;t set up virtual environments for Python, go ahead and do that now, then come back.) I have the [fink environment] (http://finkproject.org) installed on my Mac, and the Python 3 executable is in /sw/bin/python3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/jekyll/2015-05-02-installing-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 20:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/jekyll/2015-05-02-installing-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>If you are using Python 3 as a standard, the Jekyll installation from homebrew might give you problems, because the Jekyll installation out-of-the box uses the syntax higlighter Pygments, which does not work under Python 3. # more&#xA;This is the rather mysterious error I got:&#xA;$ jekyll serve --trace Configuration file: /Users/mok/github/mok0.github.io/_config.yml Source: /Users/mok/github/mok0.github.io Destination: /Users/mok/github/mok0.github.io/_site Generating... Liquid Exception: No header received back. in _posts/2015-05-02-welcome-to-jekyll.markdown Instead, use the Ruby highlighter rouge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install newer version of Ruby on OS X Yosemite</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/osx/2015-05-02-ruby-on-yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/osx/2015-05-02-ruby-on-yosemite/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how to install a newer version of Ruby on OS X Yosemite.&#xA;Following this video: https://youtu.be/jx0NrIbQbzI&#xA;$ brew update First install rbenv:&#xA;$ brew install rbenv $ brew info rbenv $ emacs .bashrc Execute (and add to .bashrc):&#xA;export RBENV_ROOT=/usr/local/var/rbenv if which rbenv &amp;gt; /dev/null; then eval &amp;quot;$(rbenv init -)&amp;quot;; fi Now we have rbenv installed. See if it works:&#xA;$ rbenv We need to install the ruby-build plugin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrosanct Linux Feature Dies</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2012-03-23-sacrosanct-linux-feature-dies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 19:07:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2012-03-23-sacrosanct-linux-feature-dies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux since 1996. Since then, the OS has undergone an amazing development, and all distributions provide an impressive high-resolution graphical interface. However, one feature has remained sacrosanct: the 6 virtual terminals. In the old days, when you had to provide timings for the video card and manually edit the xfree86 config file, it was easy to mess up the graphics display. But then, CTRL-Alt-F1 to the rescue! It was ALWAYS possible to get a terminal and consequently access to the operating system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oneiric on the Dell Mini 10: Nope</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2012-01-28-oneric-on-the-dell-mini-10-nope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 21:18:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2012-01-28-oneric-on-the-dell-mini-10-nope/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I downloaded the Ubuntu 11.10 installer and put it on an USB stick. Judging from the discussions on the net, I might be one of the only people on the planet who actually like Unity, and I was really looking forward to getting it on my netbook. In my opinion, Oneiric Ocelot is a terrific release. I have it on my workstation and I like it a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disk Quota Exceeded?</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2011-04-11-disk-quota-exceeded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 21:11:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2011-04-11-disk-quota-exceeded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The disk quota system in Linux is quite old, and if you have a&#xA;distributed workstation environment with NFS mounted shares it is not&#xA;possible in a convenient way to inform users that they have exceeded&#xA;their disk limits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free and Completely Ubuntu (2)</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2011-02-12-free-and-completely-ubuntu-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 05:05:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2011-02-12-free-and-completely-ubuntu-2/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I reported here that Tuesday evening (Feb. 8.), the popular tech-review program on danish public television channel DR2 “So Ein Ding…” dedicated an entire episode to Ubuntu.&#xA;A commenter asked for a translation, so here it is, including the program host, Nicolaj Sonne’s evocative sound effects.&#xA;Hey!&#xA;Today we jump in, and go all-in with Open Source. I have purchased a compltely new Low-budget computer, nuked Windows, and installed the free OS Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free and Completely Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2011-02-10-free-and-completely-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 21:08:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2011-02-10-free-and-completely-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday evening (Feb. 8.), the popular tech-review program on Danish public television channel DR2 “So Ein Ding…” dedicated an entire episode to Ubuntu. The program host, Nikolaj Sonne, took Ubunto for a test spin, and gives a very positive, fair and balanced review. His final verdict ends on 4 out of 6, which is extremely good, especially considering that an upgrade broke his Maverick installation in the trials (no trackpad, no keyboard) and he had to downgrade to Lucid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>80 x 25 no more...</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2010-01-12-80x25-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 05:37:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2010-01-12-80x25-no-more/</guid>
      <description>o On my workstation, I have a beautiful, large, Samsung SyncMaster 275, which is a 27.5&amp;quot; monitor. The screen area measures around 58 x 37 cm, and the nominal resolution is 1920 x 1200 pixels.&#xA;The display is beautiful and crisp, and the fonts are nice and clear on the X-display, and Kubuntu looks lovely on the monitor. My wallpaper is an image of the stunning, intriguing and slightly eery MandelBulb 3-D fractal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on the Dell Mini 10 (3)</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2009-05-27-ubuntu-on-the-dell-mini-10_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2009-05-27-ubuntu-on-the-dell-mini-10_3/</guid>
      <description>A few people have asked if the psb X driver is stable running under jaunty. It is indeed&amp;hellip; rock stable. So now that&amp;rsquo;s established, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to something else.&#xA;I really want the Dell to be a &amp;ldquo;mini-laptop&amp;rdquo; so I originally installed the ubuntu-desktop package. But I&amp;rsquo;ve felt that the response was a bit sluggish. The menus were just a few fractions of a second to appear, they kind of &amp;ldquo;rolled&amp;rdquo; on instead of just appearing etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on the Dell Mini 10 (2)</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2009-05-25-ubuntu-on-the-dell-mini-10_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 21:20:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2009-05-25-ubuntu-on-the-dell-mini-10_2/</guid>
      <description>Great news! The Dell Mini 10 now runs on Ubuntu 9.04 at full nominal resolution of 1024 x 576!&#xA;What has happened is that the Ubuntu Mobile Team has compiled and packaged kernel modules, X.org drivers, libraries to interface to kernel DRM services, etc. etc. for the Poulsbo chipset and made them available on their PPA.&#xA;Remember from my previous post, that my Mini 10 was running using the VESA driver for X.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on the Dell mini 10 (1)</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2009-05-22-ubuntu-on-the-dell-mini-10_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 12:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2009-05-22-ubuntu-on-the-dell-mini-10_1/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased a Dell Mini 10 notebook. I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to get a netbook for some time, and I was planning to one of the Asus EEE series. However, looking at one at the local computer store, I found it a bit &amp;ldquo;plastic-y&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard that Dell computers have a good build quality, so one morning, on a whim, I ordered a Dell. I told the salesman that I had no use for Windows XP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KVM with bridge</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2008-02-20-kvm-with.bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2008-02-20-kvm-with.bridge/</guid>
      <description>In the following, I will describe how to set up kvm in an environment where you want the guest virtual machines to appear as independent servers, indistinguishable from the ordinary metal boxes sitting on the floor of the office.&#xA;Host Configuration The server, called &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;octopus&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;, is a powerful HP 380 G5 machine, with an Intel dual quadcore CPU. This is a processor that has hardware virtualization enabled, which you can see by doing:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why abandon CentOS for Ubuntu?</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2007-06-06-why-abandon-centos-for-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2007-06-06-why-abandon-centos-for-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>My Linux experience My first Linux experience was around 1996 with the slackware distribution installed from floppies. I quickly went on using RedHat 3.03, and went all the way. When RedHat stopped their free version we went to Fedora Core 1. However, I quickly got fed up with Fedora&amp;rsquo;s perpetual upgrade-circus. It was just too much work upgrading all the time, and with no apparent gains (other that eye-candy stuff, but who cares).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use ssh authentication keys</title>
      <link>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2006-05-06-how-to-authenticate-using-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mok0.github.io/blog/posts/linux/2006-05-06-how-to-authenticate-using-ssh/</guid>
      <description>If you have an account on a remote computer that you use very often, it is convienient if you do not have to type your password every time you log on to another host. You can achieve this by using ssh&amp;rsquo;s authorization keys.&#xA;First, you need to generate a key-pair. A key-pair consists of two small files. One file contains your secret key, the other your public key. Your secret key is, as the name implies, secret.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
